Hello and welcome to this project on bird species prediction.
So in this project, we will create a convolutional neural network that is a CNN, and it will be able
to predict a species of a bird with the image that we supply.
So what will do?
We will use different layers and other hyper parameters for building, training and testing this multiclass
classification model.
And in this project, we will be using get us.
So the steps we need to take, we need to make this CNN or to solve this problem are firstly and show
you how you can mount your Google drive on your with your colored notebook.
This is important because after this, you don't need to download the data locally on your system.
You can just connect your drive to your Google Cloud.
We will visualize the images that we will be working on.
After that, we will analyze the dimensions to verify all the images have same dimensions or not.
The next step would be converting these images into a number and we will normalize them.
After that, we will check for class imbalance.
If all the classes have same data or not, all the classes have same images or not same number of images.
After that, we will split the data and perform one two encoding on target paper.
Next, we will create the model.
Architecture will compile the model and and then we put the model after that will plot the accuracy
and the lost against each epoch.
Then we will reprocess the test data and make predictions on it.
And in the end, we will visualize the original and predicted movement for one of the test image.
So this project, it can be used for educational purposes because it will get you a better idea of how
you can create a CNN.
You can, for the hyper parameter, doomed the model we will create to reach a hierarchy or to avoid
overthinking.
It can be used by both centuries to identify different types of words.
So let's start this project in the Google collab.
For this project.