For this project, we will be using Google Cloud as Google Cloud provides high computational power and
convolutional neural network or deep learning request that in this project we will be creating a convolutional
neural network, which will be able to predict some species of the bird.
We will create this network using different Typekit parameters like activation functions, learning
rate, but size ebooks and we will build train and test this multiclass classification model.
This project is used.
This project is based on Get us.
We will be using it.
Get us.
So let's get started.
So initially, first we will mount the Google drive on our colored notebook so that we can use that
dataset directly from our drive.
And for this, you first need to upload the data on your drive.
And then we will mount this.
So by running this command from Google Collab Import Drive and Drive Dot Mount, we are mounting over
Google Drive to Google Cloud.
So let's run this well.
So he will see that it will ask you an authorization code and in order to generate this authorization
code, you need to run this order.
So I'll go to my analytics account.
We need to allow this and copied this verification code authorization code.
So here you'll paste that code and press into.
To show us that our drivers mounted so you can see that our drivers mounted act content.
So after executing after mounting the drive, the next step would be to locate the folder wherever data
is stored on the Google Cloud to Google Cloud.
So here you can see that we will run this command, but is less content to drive my life.
Let's run this.
So here in my drive, I have started with the name of bird species dataset, so we will know that in
the next.
So this is the most important step here we are importing some of the required libraries here, you can
see that we are importing some very important libraries from very important functions for CNN from cameras,
not layers.
We are importing the layers that we will be using that is going to be max pooling 2D activation, flatten
out dense will split our data using escalator models election train to split.
We will create a sequential model, so we need to import that using catastrophic models that optimize
what we are going to use.
Optimizer.
Adam.
And similarly, all other libraries for one or two, including for open TV operations, for visualizing
the images, might not see CV two numbers and wonder.
So let's run the sale and import all the required libraries that we that we need.
So you can see that all of the libraries are important.
So in the next step and show you how we can visualize some of the images that we will be working on.
Also, we will observe the dimensions of these images.
So here you can see that have stepped up the part.
I'm using the migratory bird species dataset and in that we are using a particular folder that is American
Goldfinch and I have created a loop which will support my images for images in a row.
And we are taking images from American Goldfinch folder, and we will display around 17 images, 17
and 16 images.
So let's visualize those images and see what type of images we will be working on.
And what are the dimensions of these images, so we should be sure that all the images have the same
dimensions in order to create a model.
So here you can see you can visualize that these are the images that we will be working on.
And as you can see here, the dimensions of the images that seem to 24 to 24 for all the images.
So now let's move forward now we will set the record directly for the dataset we are using, and we
are also storing the last names of the dataset.
We will also create two empty list.
For images and limbs, so let's run this.
So after this, we are reading the images and we are converting it into an attic.
Similarly, we will also append the list created above with that image and let us label head in this
for look.
You can see that we are converting it into an attic.
And similarly, we are appending the list that we have created above and adding its label.
So let's run this.
To take some time because there are around 2000 images, thousand nine hundred images, so it will take
some time to read them, convert them into an added and also up in the list created with the image and
its label.
So it took me from 10 to 15 minutes for commodities added to buy at it.
So now let's move forward now, let us visualize.