The number of classes that we are using, so we the number of classes that we are using and how much
data they contain.
So we are checking for the data balancing here.
You can see that we are using around one, two, three, four, five and six classes with data.
Around 140 I 140, 41 in each cluster, so there is no data imbalance.
Now let's move forward.
We'll find out the number of places that will be working on and stored it into a variable that we will
be using it later in the model architecture.
So as I already told you, we're are working on six classes six species of birds.
Next, we will check the check, the shape of image and a single image.
So here you can see that we have already visualized that image above, and it was showing us 2.4 by
2.4.
And as it does a color device, the channel will be three.
That is the art you.
Now, let us check the shape of the image labels, which will be equal to the number of images that
we will be working on.
So here we can see that there are eight one one labels.
So we will be working on it one one.
That is it.
One one unique image is four different species of birds.
Now let us test to split our data using the Ashkelon.
You can see that we are splitting our data in two extreme x, just inviting latest using between the
split, and we're passing the image list and label Leicester City data to be split.
And we are setting the size 0.2.
So it will split in two 80 percent for training and 20 percent for testing.
Let's run this and split our data, so after this.
This is one of the most important step.
So here we are, normalizing the images by dividing them with 255.
And also we are reshaping the extreme and expressed.
So let's run this and normalize our images and also reshape our images in the extreme and expressed.
So after this, we will be labeled by analyzing our data that is not encoding our data to one.
Hot and coding is important because it will stop our data from getting prioritized, stop our classes
from getting prioritized.
We will also print the sequence of the classes.
Let's run this.
So here you can see that these are the classes that we will be working on.
These are American Goldfinch Barn Owl, Carmine Bita, Downy Woodpecker, Emperor Penguin and Flamingo.
These are the six classes of the birds six bird species that we will be working on.
Now, the next important step is to split that data, the training data into validation data and training
data.
So we are splitting the Extreme X, right wherever there's interest in disparate split and we are passing
the extreme and whitest white data here.
Similarly, the test size is same, but it's 80 20 percent.
So.